<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zijian Hu on Zijian Hu</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zijian Hu on Zijian Hu</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Infant-Robot Interaction as an Early Intervention Strategy</title>
      <link>/project/baby/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/baby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Infants engage in motor babbling that allows them to explore their space and learn what movements produce
desired outcomes. Less motor babbling from infants can lead to developmental delays.
Our goal is to develop a socially assistive, non-contact, infant-robot interaction system to provide contingent
positive feedback to increase exploration and expand early movement practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards this end, we are collaborating with physical therapists to create approaches to predict the developmental
status of infants using wearable sensors; running user studies that explore various robot rewards for contingent
activities for the infant, as well as measuring the infant&amp;rsquo;s ability to mimic the robot; and using reinforcement
learning to adjust the difficulty of the task presented by the robot to increase the infant&amp;rsquo;s engagement with
the task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;http://robotics.usc.edu/interaction/sponsors/desc.php?name=babies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Interaction Lab website&lt;/a&gt;
for details and related publications&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Socially Aware, Expressive, and Personalized Mobile Remote Presence:
Co-Robots as Gateways to Access to K-12 In-School Education
</title>
      <link>/project/nri_kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/nri_kids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Within the field of Human-Robot Interaction (HRI), a growing subfield is forming that focuses
specifically on interactions between one or more robots and multiple people, known as Multi-Party
Human-Robot Interaction (MP-HRI). MP-HRI encompasses the challenges of single-user HRI
(interaction dynamics, human perception, etc.) and extends them to the challenges of multi-party
interactions (within-group turn taking, dyadic dynamics, and group dynamics).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address these, MP-HRI requires new methods and approaches. Effective MP-HRI enables robotic systems
to function in many contexts, including service, support, and mediation. In realistic human contexts,
service and support robots need to work with varying numbers of individuals, particularly when working
within team structures. In mediation, robotic systems must by definition, be able to work with multiple
parties. These contexts often overlap, and algorithms that work in one context can benifit work in another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project will advance the basic research in trust and influence in MP-HRI contexts. This will involve
exploring how robots and people establish, maintain, and repair trust in MP-HRI. Specifically, this research
will examine robot group mediation for group conseling, with extensions to team performance in robot
service and support teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;http://robotics.usc.edu/interaction/sponsors/desc.php?name=nrikids&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Interaction Lab website&lt;/a&gt; for details
and related publications&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trust in Multi-Party Human-Robot Interaction</title>
      <link>/project/multi_party/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/multi_party/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Within the field of Human-Robot Interaction (HRI), a growing subfield is forming that focuses
specifically on interactions between one or more robots and multiple people, known as Multi-Party
Human-Robot Interaction (MP-HRI). MP-HRI encompasses the challenges of single-user HRI
(interaction dynamics, human perception, etc.) and extends them to the challenges of multi-party
interactions (within-group turn taking, dyadic dynamics, and group dynamics).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address these, MP-HRI requires new methods and approaches. Effective MP-HRI enables robotic systems
to function in many contexts, including service, support, and mediation. In realistic human contexts,
service and support robots need to work with varying numbers of individuals, particularly when working
within team structures. In mediation, robotic systems must by definition, be able to work with multiple
parties. These contexts often overlap, and algorithms that work in one context can benifit work in another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project will advance the basic research in trust and influence in MP-HRI contexts. This will involve
exploring how robots and people establish, maintain, and repair trust in MP-HRI. Specifically, this research
will examine robot group mediation for group conseling, with extensions to team performance in robot
service and support teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;http://robotics.usc.edu/interaction/projects/desc2.php?name=multiparty_support&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Interaction Lab website&lt;/a&gt;
for details and related publications&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
